job.com 2015-12-18

# Job.com Jobs - Start your job search and find employment today!

_Effective Date: 01/09/2015_

### Job.com's Privacy Information - Overview

This privacy policy applies to www.job.com owned and operated by Job.com, Inc "Job.com". This privacy policy describes how Job.com, Inc. collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site: www.job.com. Job.com is committed to protecting the privacy of our users. We want to provide a safe, secure user experience while on our Web site www.Job.com. We will use our best efforts to ensure that the information you submit to us remains private, and is used only for the purposes as set forth herein. The following reflects our commitment to you. 

Job.com, Inc. has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this site www.Job.com. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request. 

### Information About All Job.com Visitors

We gather information about all of our users collectively, such as what areas users visit most frequently and what services users access the most. We use such information in the aggregate and not on an individual basis. This information helps us determine what is most beneficial for our users, and how we can develop a better overall website for our users. This information may be shared with our partners, but only in the aggregate, so that they too may develop a better overall career website for you, as well. 

### Information About You Specifically

In some instances, such as when you sign up to use a service, enter into a contest, or purchase a product, we may need more specific personal information about you, such as name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card number, etc. We may use that information to make you aware of additional products and services which may be of interest to you, send newsletters or service related emails if our service is temporarily down, provide you professional resume services, allow our professional resume writers to contact you for an interview, or to contact you regarding site changes. We may also ask you for other information, such as feedback regarding the site, the types of jobs you are interested in, etc., Again, in an effort to develop for you and deliver to you the best possible career website. 

When applying for a job listed directly on Job.com or signing to become a member, we will ask you for additional information such as desired salary, ethnicity, career level, education level, and whether or not you have served in the U.S. Military. Some of this information is used as part of your profile that potential employers will be able to view if you post a resume and opt to have your resume viewable by employers. Specifically, ethnicity and gender are not viewable by employers. 

### General Information Disclosure

We do not disclose, share, sell, trade or rent information about your individual visits to Job.com, or personal information that you provide, such as your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card number, etc., to any outside parties other than as disclosed within this privacy policy. 

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as a credit card processing company to process payments, a third party customer service company that may offer customer support on our behalf. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

We use a third party service provider to send text messages to you regarding job alerts, should you choose to use this service. By opting into this service, Job.com will share your information with the third-party for the sole purpose of fulfilling this service on your behalf. To opt-out from receiving text alerts you may follow the unsubscribe instructions located at the bottom of each text message or email our third party service provider directly. 

We offer you the ability to utilize our career tools like resume writing, resume distribution, and education information services which are hosted by third party service providers however framed by Job.com. Although this section of the site has the look and feel of Job.com you are on our third party service provider's site and their privacy policy governs the collection and use of the information collected there. Your information is then shared back with Job.com in order for us to provide you the services you have requested. 

We may disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. 

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

### Featured Programs

On certain pages of our site we offer programs of third parties, such as colleges. The information collected on these pages is collected by Job.com and then passed on to the featured program entity to fulfill your information request. If you do not wish to have your personal information shared in this manner please do not fill out these forms, if you have already provided your information and do not wish to be contacted by these third parties please contact them directly. 

### Resumes

Since Job.com is a career site, we give you the option of putting your resume in our database, to be searched by prospective employers / recruiters or responding to individual ads with your resume. If you allow your resume to be searchable, then all recruiters with access to our resume database product will have access to your resume. We use our best efforts to grant access to this database only to recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters, and human resource professionals. However, we are not responsible if some other third party, such as someone posing as the aforementioned and evades security measures and gains access to the database, and, subsequently, your resume. You may remove your resume from our searchable database at any time by logging into your account and selecting mange my resumes under the Jobseeker Menu. However, recruiters who have access to the database may have retained a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. We are not responsible for the retention, use, or privacy of resumes in these instances. 

You also have the ability to post your resume to other sites, have your resume critiqued by a professional, and participate in Job.com's third-party featured offers. We may share information such as your name and email address with third-parties for the sole purpose of fulfilling your opt-in service or information request. If you wish to opt-out of any third-party offers, you must contact the third-party directly. 

### Email

To connect you with account information, jobs, and career tools, we will communicate with you via email using the email address provided during registration. Current Job.com members may unsubscribe from Job.com emails at any time by either clicking on the "Manage Newsletters" link in the footer of the email or logging into your account and navigating to the "Newsletter Subscription Manager" located under "Jobseeker Menu." Removing your email from our list may take up to 5 business days. For those that wish to opt-out of all email from Job.com go here. 

### Updating Your Personal Information

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delete inaccuracies, or deactivate your account by making the change on our member information page, or by emailing us at privacy@Job.com. We will respond to your access request within 30 days. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at privacy@Job.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

### Profiles

Profiles are only shared with employers when a job seeker has opted-in to allow the employer to view their resume. The profile information is collected when you post your resume to apply for a job listed directly on Job.com. No one else on the site may view your profile at any time. You may update your visibility to employers by by logging into your account and selecting "Manage My Resumes" under the Jobseeker Menu. 

If you believe that an unauthorized profile has been created about you, you can request for it be removed by contacting us at privacy@job.com. 

### Cookies and other Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Job.com, Inc. and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers such as customer support or advertising service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking usersâ€™ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to remember users' settings, for authentication, and to customize the user experience. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. 

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. (We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. Or We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality. 

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. 

Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own [management tools](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager06.html) for removing HTML5 LSOs. 

### Targeted or Behavioral Advertising:

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our site, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at privacy@job.com. 

### Blog

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at privacy@job.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. You may also post a comment on our blog through a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy. 

### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacy@job.com. 

### Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

### Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. 

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personal information. 

This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this Web site. 

### Tell a Friend

We offer you the ability to share job posts and articles with friends through online social networking sites or by using adthis. Your friends email address and name will be collected if you choose to use the email feature and will be used to send them a one- time email asking them to visit the site or the job post you requested. We do not have any access to this information. 

### Privacy Commitment Changes

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about Job.com's privacy commitment, please feel free to email us at Privacy@Job.com. 

Job.com, Inc.  
100 Riverside Pkwy, Ste 201  
Fredericksburg, VA 22406  
(540) 374-5694 

Thank you for using Job.com. We'll continue working to make this your favorite website to manage your career.
